DEEPTI DEEPTI

850-320-5794 | deepti.deepti.se@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/DeeptiDeepti

Solutions-Driven Software Engineer with professional experience in modular and object-oriented programming. Well-versed in all phases of software development lifecycle (SDLC). Proven success in incorporating business requirements into cost-effective, secure and user-friendly solutions.



Profile: www.deeptideepti.com

SKILLS

- 6 years of Software Development
- JAVA programmer
- Agile Development
- SDLC Strategy, Planning & Leadership
- Performance Optimization

- Masters in Computer Science
- Business Analyst
- TOGAF Certified Requirements Engineer
- Test Strategies and Automation
- Excellent communication skills

TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY

Languages: JAVA, C#, SQL/PL-SQL, ASP.NET

Frameworks: J2EE, Microsoft .NET Framework 3, VB .NET

Databases: Oracle (9i, 10g, 11g), Microsoft SQL Server 2010, SPARQL

Software: Maven, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Tomcat, Microsoft IIS, JIRA, SQL Server Profiler, Visual Studio,

HP LoadRunner

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Xerox-Conduent

Tallahassee, FL, 06/2011 – Present

Design, develop and support DriveSafe Enforcement Systems to provide road safety solutions for 50+clients. Focused end to end development of 4 versions of Citeweb application.

- Developed secure RESTful web services (supporting both XML and JSON) to provide sensitive violation details to authenticated clients.
- Designed and developed processes to interact with OPEX scanner API's to extract application specific information and created associated stored procedures.
- Achieved 20% increase in notice generation efficiency by identifying performance bottlenecks.
- Lead of Change Control Board (CCB) for top-tier revenue generating projects.
- Formulated requirements for upcoming version of Citeweb application with use case driven analysis to construct complete design workflows.
- Test Strategy developer defined Test Plans driven by risk-based prioritization of functional requirements.
- Managed UAT and collaborated closely with clients to refine key features such as Violation Approval and Court Processing.
- Automated test scripts resulting in 25% reduction of maintenance efforts.

Code and Architecture Refactoring – Developer:

Designed and developed event extraction processes for clients that significantly use Mesa camera technology for capturing images and videos. Enhanced and refactored code to adapt to rapid changes in Mesa technology.

- Achieved 60% increase in generated revenue by scaling the functionality to account for multiple violations across multiple lanes.
- Created API's for the Violation processing application Citeweb, to facilitate approval of violations from State clients.
- Trained and mentored programmers in project-specific programming methodologies and practices.
- Reduced 40% of maintenance costs by introducing generic templates and developing workflows.

Legacy Application – Developer:

Developed scripts to collect media assets from various types of speed cameras; and processed the metadata to create a possible violation event package.

- Enhanced the existing functionality of violation event packaging from its creation to notice printing and mailing process.
- Created scripts and stored procedures to generate reports and implement the notice creation process for a violation.

Computer Science Graduate Assistant Florida State University

Tallahassee, FL, 08/2009 – 05/2011

Software Engineer - Intern National Informatics Center (NIC)

New Delhi, India, 05/2008 – 07/2008

Developed Ontology, using *Protégé* application, to evaluate the role of Semantically Driven Architecture for e-Governance.

- Designed and developed a JAVA-based search application capable of performing semantic queries.
- Achieved 40% improvement in search efficiency by employing the developed ontology to refine metadata
- Published 2 research papers in an international journal.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science – 05/2011

Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL, USA

Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology – 05/2009

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, Delhi, India

PUBLICATIONS

Deepti, Rama Hariharan.(2008). **Semantically Driven Architecture for e-Governance**. *International Conference on e-Government*, (pp. 245-250). New Delhi. (Adjudged as the best paper)

Deepti, Rama Hariharan (2009). Role of Ontologies in e-Governance.

Electronics Information & Planning, 92-97.